coromant.com 2019-08-20

# Legal notice

**Please read this Legal Notice carefully before using this website (the "Site").**

Material contained on the Site is provided by Sandvik AB (publ), reg.no 556000-3468, SE-811 81 Sandviken, Sweden ("Sandvik") and the Sandvik Group as a service and should be used for information purposes only.

By accessing the Site you agree to the following terms. If you do not agree to them, you should not use the Site.

##### Copyright Information

The contents of the Site are copyright 2000-2018 Sandvik AB (publ) (or its subsidiaries). All rights reserved.

The information on the Site, included but not limited to, text, graphics, images, audio clips and software is the property of Sandvik and is protected by Swedish and international copyright laws. Unauthorised use or distribution of any material on the Site may violate copyright, trademark, and other laws and is subject to civil as well as criminal sanctions.

The Site or any proportion of it may not, except where otherwise indicated, be reproduced, duplicated, copied, transferred, distributed, stored or otherwise exploited for any commercial use without prior written permission by Sandvik. Modifications to the contents of the Site are expressly prohibited.

You agree to prevent any unauthorised copying of the materials and to ensure that all employees, where applicable, of your organisation adheres to these limitations.

The Site may contain images that are subject to the copyright rights of third parties.

##### Trademark Information

Unless otherwise indicated, all trademarks, brand names, corporate logos and emblems displayed on the Site are the property of Sandvik, its affiliates, its licensors or joint venture partners.

Sandvik's trademarks, brand names, corporate logos and emblems may not be used any way without the prior written permission from Sandvik.

##### No Warranties or Representations

INFORMATION ON THE SITE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. IN NO EVENT WILL SANDVIK BE LIABLE TO ANY PARTY FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL OR OTHER CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES FOR ANY USE OF THE SITE, OR ON ANY OTHER HYPERLINKED WEBSITE INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, ANY LOST PROFITS, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, LOSS OF PROGRAMS OR OTHER DATA ON YOUR HANDLING SYSTEM OR OTHERWISE, ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE THE INFORMATION, EVEN IF SANDVIK ARE ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.

Sandvik makes no warranties or representations whatsoever in respect of use and content of any other website which you may access through the Site. Such access is provided only as a convenience and does not mean that Sandvik endorses or accepts any responsibilities for the contents or the use of such web sites. In addition, you must take precautions and to ensure that whatever you select for your use is free of such items as viruses, worms, Trojan horses and other items of a destructive nature.

Furthermore, Sandvik does not warrant the accuracy or completeness of the information, text, graphics, links or other items that may be contained on the Site. The information contained on the Site may be changed at any time without prior notification. However, Sandvik makes no commitment to update the information or other material contained on the Site.

##### User Submissions

Any material, information or other communications you transmit or post to the Site ("Submissions") will be considered non-confidential, non-exclusive, royalty free, irrevocable, fully sub licensable and non-proprietary. Sandvik will have no obligations concerning Submissions.

Sandvik will be free to disclose, copy, distribute, incorporate, modify and otherwise use Submissions, together with all data, images, audio clips, text and other things embodied therein, for any and all commercial and non-commercial purposes.

Should you submit personal data to Sandvik via the Site or otherwise, you consent to Sandvik's use of such data for the purposes of evaluating your information and use connected to the marketing of Sandvik's products and services. This includes the right to transfer the submitted data to third parties and for potential publication on the Internet. Sandvik is responsible under Swedish law for the processing of personal data. Sandvik can be contacted to address cases of incorrect data or other issues related to the personal data. For more information please refer to Sandvik's [Privacy Statement](https://www.home.sandvik/en/about-this-site/privacy/privacy-statement/ "Privacy Statement").

##### Other

Sandvik may at any time revise the terms of this Legal Notice by updating it. Further, Sandvik reserves in its sole discretion, the right to monitor and discontinue the Site's availability at any time without prior notification. If any term, condition or provision of this Legal Notice is determined to be unlawful, invalid, void or for any reason unenforceable, the validity and enforceability of the remaining terms, conditions and provisions shall not in any way be affected or impaired thereby.  

* * *

## Privacy Policy  

The text below sets out the Privacy Policy for this website (www.sandvik.coromant.com). It deals with how your data is handled whilst interacting with Sandvik Coromant online. Further information about Sandvik's commitment to protecting your privacy can be found in the [Sandvik Privacy Statement](https://www.home.sandvik/en/about-this-site/privacy/privacy-statement/ "Sandvik privacy statement").  

#### An overview of data protection  

##### General  

The following gives an overview of what happens to your personal information when you visit our website. Personal information covers any data which may be used to identify you personally. Detailed information on the subject of data protection can be found within this Privacy Policy.

##### Data collection on our website  

_Who is responsible for the data collection on this website?_  

The website operator processes the data collected on this website. The operator's contact details can be found within this Privacy Policy.

_How does Sandvik Coromant collect your data?_  

Some data is collected when you provide it to us. This could, for example, be data you enter on a contact form.

Other data is collected automatically by our IT systems when you visit the website. This data is primarily technical data such as the browser and operating system you are using upon accessing a web page on the website. This data is collected automatically as soon as you enter the website.  

_What does Sandvik Coromant use your data for?_  

Part of the data is collected to ensure the proper functioning of the website. Other data can be used to analyze how visitors use the website.  

_What rights do you have regarding your data?_  

You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the purpose of its collection at no charge. You also have the right to request that it be corrected, blocked, or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in this Privacy Policy if you have further questions about the issue of privacy and data protection. Should the need arise, you have the right to address a complaint with the authorities regulating the use of personal data.

##### Analytics and third-party tools  

When visiting the website, statistical analyses may be made of your interaction with it. This happens primarily using cookies and tracking scripts/analytics. The analysis of your interaction is usually anonymous, i.e. Sandvik Coromant& will not be able to identify you from this data. You can prevent disclosure of your interaction with the website by configuring the privacy settings in your web browser. See section below "Data collection on our website > Cookies".  

#### General information and mandatory information  

##### Data protection  

The operators of this website take the protection of your personal data very seriously. We treat your personal data as confidential and in accordance with statutory data protection regulations and this Privacy Policy.  

If you use this website, various pieces of personal data will be collected. Personal information is any data with which you could be personally identified. This privacy policy explains what information Sandvik collects and what it is used for. It also explains how and for what purpose this happens.

Please note that data transmitted via the internet (e.g. via email communication) may be subject to security breaches. Complete protection of your data from third parties who may illegally gain access to it cannot be guaranteed.

##### Revocation of your consent to the processing of your data

Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. The data processed before Sandvik Coromant receives your request may still be legally processed.

You have the right to know what data Sandvik Coromant holds about you. You have unrestricted access to that information and have it corrected if inaccurate or out of date. You can also object to Sandvik Coromant's use of data about you and/or request that use of your data be withheld. You also have the right to request that your personal data be completely erased. Where applicable, you may request to receive your data in a machine readable format and have it transferred to yourself or a third party. To exercise any of these rights, [use this form](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/2160cba7-ed7f-4dbf-b243-72bc5623b4e2).

##### Right to file complaints with regulatory authorities  

If there has been a breach of data protection legislation, the person affected may file a complaint with the relevant regulatory authorities.

##### Right to data portability  

You have the right to have data that Sandvik Coromant processes based on your consent or in fulfillment of a contract automatically delivered to yourself or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. Should you request a direct transfer of data, this can only be done is cases where it is technically feasible to do so.

##### SSL or TLS encryption  

This website uses SSL or TLS encryption for security reasons and for the protection of the transmission of confidential content, such as any enquiries you send to Sandvik Coromant as the website operator. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon is displayed in your browser's address bar.  

If SSL or TLS encryption is activated, third parties cannot read the data you transfer to Sandvik Coromant.

##### Encrypted payments on this website  

If you enter into a contract which requires you to send Sandvik Coromant your payment information (e.g. account number for direct debits), your data is required to process your payment.  

Payment transactions using common means of payment (Visa/MasterCard, direct debit) are only made via encrypted SSL or TLS connections. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon in your browser line is visible.

In the case of encrypted communication, third parties cannot read any payment details you submit to Sandvik Coromant.

##### Information, blocking, deletion  

As permitted by law, you have the right to be provided at any time with information free of charge about any of your personal data that is stored as well as its origin, the recipient and the purpose for which it has been processed. You also have the right to have this data corrected, blocked or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in this legal notice if you have further questions on the topic of personal data.

##### Opposition to promotional emails  

We hereby expressly prohibit the use of contact data published in the context of this website's legal notice with regard to sending promotional and informational materials not expressly requested. The website operator reserves the right to take specific legal action if unsolicited advertising material, such as email spam, is received.  

#### Data protection officer  

##### Statutory data protection officer  

If you want to get in contact with our Privacy Officer, you can do so by sending an email to [privacy@sandvik.com](mailto:privacy@sandvik.com).  

#### Data collection on our website  

##### Cookies  

Some of our web pages use cookies. Cookies do not harm your computer and do not contain any viruses. Cookies help make our website more user-friendly, efficient and secure. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser.  

Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies." They are automatically deleted after your visit. Other cookies remain in your device's memory until you delete them. These cookies make it possible to recognize your browser when you next visit the website for the purposes of avoiding the re-entry of basic information.  

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions, to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.  

Cookies that are necessary to allow electronic communications or to provide certain functions you wish to use (such as the shopping cart) are stored pursuant to Art. 6 paragraph 1(f) of the European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This website legitimately uses cookies to ensure an optimized service provided free of technical errors. If other cookies (such as those used to analyze your surfing behavior) are also stored, they will be treated separately in this Privacy Policy.

##### Server log files  

The website provider automatically collects and stores information on each page request done by your browser in "server log files".  

This data contains:  

  * IP address  

  * Browser type and browser version  

  * Page address (URL)  

  * Time of the request  

This data will not be combined with data from other sources.  

Furthermore, information about errors that occur in the system and requests that are made to backend systems are also stored for trouble shooting purposes. This data may contain personal information such as email (if you are registered with our website) and IP address. All such data is deleted after 14 days and is not combined with data from other sources.  

The basis for this data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

##### Contact form  

Should you send us questions via the contact form, we will collect the data entered on the form, including the contact details you provide, to answer your question and any follow-up questions. We do not share this information without your permission.  

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a) GDPR. You may revoke your consent at any time. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.  

We will retain the data you provide on the contact form until you request its deletion, revoke your consent for its storage, or the purpose for its storage no longer pertains (e.g. after fulfilling your request). Any mandatory statutory provisions, especially those regarding mandatory data retention periods, remain unaffected by this provision.

#### Registration on this website  

You can register on our website in order to access functionality not available to anonymous website visitors. The input data will only be used for the purpose of using the respective website or service for which you have registered. The mandatory information requested during registration must be provided in full. Otherwise, we will reject your registration.  

To inform you about important changes such as those within the scope of our website or technical changes, we will use the email address specified during registration.  

We will process the data provided during registration only based on your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a) GDPR. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.  

We will continue to store the data collected during registration for as long as you remain registered on our website. Statutory retention periods remain unaffected.

##### Processing of data (customer and contract data)  

We collect, process, and use personal data only insofar as it is necessary to establish, or modify legal relationships with us (master data). This is done based on Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract. We collect, process and use your personal data when accessing our website (usage data) only to the extent required to enable you to access our products and services and for Sandvik Coromant to invoice you accordingly.  

Collected customer data shall be deleted after completion of the order or termination of the business relationship. Legal retention periods remain unaffected.

##### Data transmitted when entering into a contract with online shops, retailers, and mail order  

We transmit personally identifiable data to third parties only to the extent required to fulfill the terms of your contract, for example, to companies entrusted to deliver goods to your location or banks entrusted to process your payments. Your data will not be transmitted for any other purpose unless you have given your express permission to do so. Your data will not be disclosed to third parties for advertising purposes without your express consent.  

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) GDRP, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

##### Data transferred when signing up for services and digital content  

We transmit personally identifiable data to third parties only to the extent required to fulfill the terms of your contract with us, for example, to banks entrusted to process your payments.  

Your data will not be transmitted for any other purpose unless you have given your express permission to do so. Your data will not be disclosed to third parties for advertising purposes without your express consent.  

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.  

#### Analytics and advertising

##### Google Analytics  

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service. It is operated by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.  

Google Analytics uses cookies. These are text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to, and stored by a Google server located in the USA.  

Google Analytics cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

##### IP (Internet Protocol) anonymization  

We have activated the IP anonymization feature on this website. Your IP address will be shortened by Google within the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area prior to transmission to the United States. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services regarding website activity and Internet usage for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with any other data held by Google.

##### Google Tag Manager  

We use Google Tag Manager (GTM) for tracking and analytics. GTM does not collect any personal information. It is a tool that automatically updates the code snippets of tags that, in turn, may collect sensitive information. GTM does not use these data. However, even if you decline cookies or deactivate URL-based session tracking, tags managed via GTM will still be enabled. For more details, see <https://www.google.com/analytics/tag-manager/use-policy/>.

##### DoubleClick by Google  

We use DoubleClick, an ad serving service provided by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. DoubleClick by Google uses cookies to personalize ads. Your browser is assigned a pseudonymous ID used to track the ads that have been served to your browser and to identify those you have clicked. The cookies enable Google and its partners to select and display ads based on your browsing behavior on websites including ours. They do not collect any personal details. The collected information will be transferred to Google’s US-based mainframe. Google fully complies with the Privacy Shield framework implemented by The European Union and the US Department of Commerce. Google does not pass on this information to any third party unless required by law, or for data processing purposes required by the client. Furthermore, the information will not be correlated in any way to any other data collected by Google. By using our website you agree to Google collecting and processing information to the extent and for the purposes mentioned above.  

If you do not agree with Google using cookies, you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies. However, declining cookies means that certain functional aspects of our webpage may no longer be available to you. Moreover, you can object to data being collected, transferred and processed by Google by downloading a browser plug-in that deactivates DoubleClick. Alternatively, go to the Digital Advertising Alliance webpage and disable DoubleClick, [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

##### Google AdWords Conversion Tracking  

This website uses ad conversion tracking services provided by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. Google uses cookies created on your computer to analyze your browsing behavior. Conversion tracking cookies are created as a result of you clicking on one of the adverts served by Google. Cookies used for conversion tracking do not collect any personal information. If you do not agree with your browsing activities being tracked by Google, you can change your browser settings in order to block all cookies from googleadservices.com. You may also exercise your right to opt out of tracking by visiting <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. If you would like to find out more about how conversion tracking works, and your options when it comes to preventing Google from using cookie-based information, check out <https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated>.

Conversion cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.  

##### Google Remarketing  

We use a remarketing tool provided by provided by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. The tool helps personalizing adverts based on individual visitor preference within the Google Display Network. We use this automated service to show you products you may be interested in, with the ads chosen based on your clicking behavior when browsing our website during your most recent visit.  The service uses cookies created on your computer that help recognize you when you re-visit websites that are members of the Google Display Network. A cookie is a little text file created on your computer when browsing our website. Google collects your URL request, your IP address, browser type, and language as well as time and date of the visit. This information is used to identify the browser on a computer, which, in turn, enables Google Display Network to pick, and show ads based on content viewed on websites that also employ the remarketing tool during your previous browser session. If you have previously agreed to your browser history and your Google account being synchronized (<https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated>), and to your Google account details being used to show you personalized ads, Google’s remarketing tool will be enabled across a range of devices. This means that Google uses your Google ID to recognize you on different mobile devices, but does not collect any personal information in the process. If you do not agree with Google collecting information to be used in its remarketing tool, you can disable the tool by making the necessary changes to the Google ad settings at <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>.

##### Custom Audience Pixel  

We use Custom Audience Pixel, a service provided by Facebook Inc., that enables us to show personalized ads to people visiting our website whilst being logged on to Facebook. In order to do so, we have added Facebook’s Pixel code snippet on certain web pages, which establishes a link to Facebook’s servers, telling Facebook that you have visited our webpage. Facebook adds this information to your Facebook account. For more details about how Facebook collects and uses your personal data, and what you can do to protect your sensitive information, please refer to Facebook’s privacy policy available at <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. Alternatively, you can object to Facebook showing you personalized ads using this link: <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_>.

##### Facebook Pixel  

We use Pixel, a Facebook tool that helps use optimize our advertising on the social network pages operated by Facebook Inc, 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. You have agreed to the use of the tool by ticking “I agree to the use of Facebook Pixel”. Facebook Pixel supports the statistical analysis and impact assessment of ads displayed on Facebook in the context of marketing research. We only receive depersonalized data that do not render visitors identifiable. However, as Facebook stores and processes the data, this enables Facebook to correlate the information to user profiles and use them for its own marketing activities (see Facebook Privacy Policy at <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>). This may include a cookie being created on your computer.

##### Marketo  

We use Marketo, a marketing automation platform; data processing is based on Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR. You may revoke your consent at any time by unsubscribing to our newsletters. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed. Marketo is used to help us understand your use of the website and tailor communication to your interests. Marketo technology uses cookies and web beacons to create a ‘profile’ of your browsing activity and email interaction. While Marketo is a third party, the service they provide us allows us to use their functionality in a first party context, and we directly control the setting of Marketo cookies as well as the data they collect via our website.  

We use Marketo for our newsletters, if you do not want your usage of the newsletter to be analyzed by Marketo, you will have to unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a link in every newsletter we send.  

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you cancel your subscription.  

For more information, see the privacy policy of Marketo at <https://documents.marketo.com/legal/privacy/>.  

#### Plug-ins and tools  

##### YouTube  

Our website uses plugins from YouTube, which is operated by Google. The operator of the pages is YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA.  

If you visit one of our pages featuring a YouTube plugin, a connection to the YouTube servers is established. Here the YouTube server is informed about which of our pages you have visited.  

If you are logged in to your YouTube account, YouTube allows you to associate your browsing behavior directly with your personal profile. You can prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account.  

YouTube is used to help make our website appealing. This constitutes a justified interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR.  

##### Geolocation Services  

We offer location-enabled services within our website via Bing Maps. If you use those functions, they may receive information about your actual location (such as GPS signals sent by a mobile device) or information that can be used to approximate a location. You can generally enable or disable your location services in your device or browser settings.  

##### Social networks  

We use "AddThis", a bookmarking plugin from AddThis, 1595 Spring Hill Road, Suite 300, Vienna, VA, 22182, USA ("AddThis"). AddThis allows you to bookmark pages and share content from our website on social networks. Cookies are used when AddThis is used. The data generated in this process (e.g. time of use or browser language) is transmitted to AddThis in the United States and processed there. Further information on the data collected and how AddThis uses it is available at <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy>. You can find information on the nature of the data processed and the intended use thereof on this page. We do not process the data in question. When you use AddThis, you also agree to the processing of data by AddThis. You can refuse the use of your data at any time by opting out directly with AddThis at <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out>.

##### Chat integration solutions  

We use Unify and Velaro as chat integration solutions.  

Unify and Velaro may collect data when you submit a chat request. Such data may include information about your hardware and software environment, username or other authentication information.  

For further details around Unify’s privacy and security commitments, you may address any concern about Unify’s use of your Personal Data to Unify’s data protection officer. You may also send any inquiries about information on Unify’s use of personal data, as well as requests for the blocking or deletion or correction of your personal data, to Unify’s data protection officer. The Unify data protection officer can be contacted via email: guido.stueper@unify.com.  

##### Surveys/customer feedback with Usabilla  

We use “Usabilla for Websites”, provided from Usabilla B.V. (Rokin 16, 1012 KR Amsterdam, Niederlande, "Usabilla" in the following). Usabilla collects feedback of website visitors to enable us to analyze and improve the usage our website as well as occurring technical problems. Whenever a visitor uses the feedback button, which is visible on our website or another kind of the possibility to give feedback a cookie is set on his computer and the browser connects to the server of Usabilla. During this process, Usabilla collects information like device, operating system, browser, display resolution and saves it in a pseudonymized operational profile. Further information like email address or feedback answers are only collected if the user supplies the data actively. The cookie is only set when a user clicks on the appropriate button. After this, you can disagree with the collection by deleting the cookie from your browser. This applies as long as you click on the feedback button again. Please read the “how-to” from Usabilla for further information: <https://support.usabilla.com/hc/en-us/categories/200958969-How-tos>.

##### CoroPlus® ToolGuide

We use CoroPlus® ToolGuide to assist tool and cutting data recommendations. This is a stand-alone web based widget whose interface is embedded into the website. The widget is hosted outside of the website environment, in North Europe data center of Microsoft Azure. The widget receives the user login (typically email) as user identification and allows users to create and maintain his/her own definitions of CoroPlus® ToolGuide specific entities (machine tool and workpiece material).  

The widget also temporarily for period of 3 months stores information about by user performed cutting data calculation and recommendation for the purposes of further development of the software. Except for the email address the widget does not receive or capture any personal data.

##### Online Tool Assembly  

We use Online Tool Assembly to enable the creation of an assembled tool by a website visitor. This is a stand-alone web based widget whose interface is embedded into the website. The widget is hosted outside of the website environment, in North Europe data center of Microsoft Azure. It operates using Sandvik Coromant's product data by exchanging product article code identity information with Sandvik's Tooling Internet Business Platform (TIBP) and downloading product data on demand from Product Data Highway (PDH) services. As an output it creates Generic Tooling Classification (GTC) package of assembly that users can download. The widget does not receive or capture any personal data.

##### Online 3D Viewer  

We use Online 3D Viewer to enable viewing of 3D models. This is a standalone web based widget whose interface is embedded into the website. The widget is hosted outside of the website environment, in North Europe data center of Microsoft Azure.It operates using file URI information provided by the website of particular product 3D model and visualizes it to its user for informational purposes only. The widget does not receive or capture any personal data.

##### Online 2D Viewer   

We use Online 2D Viewer to enable viewing of 2D models. This is a standalone web based widget whose interface is embedded into the website. The widget is hosted outside of the website environment, in North Europe data center of Microsoft Azure. It operates using file Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) information provided by the website of particular product 2D model and visualizes it to its user for informational purposes only. The widget does not receive or capture any personal data.

##### Metal Cutting Technology E-learning  

We use WordPress Learndash for tracking user progress of the Metal Cutting Technology E-learning. A user's email address is stored and used for displaying progress through training modules and to enable the printing of certificates.  

#### Payment service provider  

##### Adyen  

Sandvik Coromant uses Adyen, an online payment services provider which is complementary to Sandvik Coromant's existing invoicing procedure. If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Adyen stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted. All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.
